Did you know that Google name is originally a play on the word Googol,
你知道谷歌的名称 Google 一开始只是巧妙地借用了单词 Googol 吗？
which is a mathematical term for a massive number equal to one followed by 100 zeros?
Googol (古戈尔) 是个数学术语 指的是一个很大的数 即 1 后面跟着 100 个 0
Google liked it so much because it seemed like
谷歌很喜欢这个词 因为它看起来
there was as many web pages over the Internet.
就像因特网里有的网页那么多
In fact, Googol is so massive that there is
事实上 古戈尔太大了
no numerical data type in Java that can actually store it.
Java 里没有一个值数据类型能存放它
Even a long data type can store only a number up to two to the 63,
就算是长整型数据能储存的最大值也只是 2 的 63 次方
which is merely a 19 digit long number.
不过是个 19 位数罢了
In fact, there are far less electrons in the entire universe than one single Googol.
事实上 整个宇宙的电子数远少于一个古戈尔
On the other hand, we can store the number as a string of
不过我们可以把古戈尔储存为一串字符
characters since it's only made up of 101 characters,
因为它只由 101 个字符组成
it can actually fit in a string in Java.
所以 Java 里的一个字符串就能容纳它
We can't really do any mathematical operation with it since it's stored in a string,
虽然把古戈尔储存在一个字符串里 我们无法对其实施任何数学运算
but we can use the string to do other stuff like printed out for example.
但我们可以用这个字符串来做其它事情 比如输出该字符串
However, typing down 101 characters seems a bit tedious.
然而 输出 101 个字符似乎有点枯燥
So why don't we use a while loop to build that string for us?
那我们何不用 while 循环来创建这个字符串呢？
We start with initializing the string with just one,
先把字符串初始化为 1
and then we can concatenate a zero string to it inside a while loop.
然后我们可以在 while 循环内为其串接一个字符串 0
The while loop would keep checking if the length of the string is still less than 101,
while 循环会不断检查字符串长度是否仍小于 101
and it would keep concatenating another zero to it until the length becomes 101.
在长度变为 101 之前 每循环一次 字符串都会多串接一个 0
So we need to keep track of the string length.
所以我们需要跟踪字符串长度
For that, we declare and initialize a variable len,
因此 我们需要声明一个变量 即 len 然后将其初始化
which is an integer and we assign it the value of googol.length.
也就是声明变量为整数 然后将 googol.length 的值赋给该变量
The function length calculates the length of
length 函数会计算这个字符串的长度
that string and returns it and stores it into the variable len.
返回出结果并将值赋给变量 len
Then we also update that variable inside the loop so it's
然后我们还要在循环里更新这个变量
always keeping track of the length of the string googol.
使其一直跟踪字符串 googol 的长度
Can you think of what the while condition should be?
你知道 while 条件该怎么写吗？
Remember, we need to keep iterating over this loop for as long as
记住 我们需要不断迭代这个循环
googol is actually still smaller than the length that it should be which is a 101.
直到 googol 不再小于 101 这个长度为止